symbian.com 2005-12-17

# Symbian Ltd: Privacy policy

This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with:  
Terms and conditions of use

## 1\. Introduction

Symbian Limited (referred to as "Symbian", "we, or "our") is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to the Symbian web sites (including the web sites at the following uniform resource locaters: <http://www.symbian.com/> and [Symbian Signed](http://www.symbiansigned.com/) together with all related discussion forums, directories and databases) (the "web sites"). We have put in place policies and procedures to protect personal information we collect about you in order to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998. This privacy policy explains how we collect and use the information we collect about you. If you do not agree with this privacy policy, please do not use this web site. By accessing and using this web site, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy.

## 2\. Services

Symbian provides details on the web site about its business practices including details of its partners and licensees, professional services providers, third party software developers, and independent software vendors (together the "Symbian Community"). The web sites also includes details about the Symbian 32 bit operating system , and the Symbian Developer Network and include authorised access to interactive discussion forums, directories and/or databases, together with details of related products and/or services available to you (together the "Services").

## 3\. What type of information is collected and how long is it retained?

To provide you with the Services, we collect certain personal information about you when you subscribe and register with us for membership of the Symbian Developer Network, or in any other circumstances on any of the web sites. When you register with us, a unique username and password may be provided to you to enable you to access the web sites. The information we collect may include, but is not limited to, your name, address, bank account details, credit card details, telephone number, email address and work details.

We do not collect any sensitive personal information such as information on your racial or ethnic origins, political opinions, religious beliefs, trade union affiliations, sexual life, health or criminal history.

## 4\. How is information collected?

We may collect personal information about you from the following sources:

> 4.1 Personal details registered by yourself in relation to the Symbian Developer Network
> 
> 4.2 Personal details registered by yourself in relation to Symbian Signed;
> 
> 4.3 Personal details registered by yourself in other ways e.g. to receive email or SMS message updates or information;
> 
> 4.4 Information about your visits to the web sites;
> 
> 4.5 Analysis of visitor traffic using cookies and standard web logs.

When you view the web sites by hypertext link from another web site or when you hypertext link to another web sites from the web sites, we may store the names of such web sites for our own internal administration.

## 5\. How long is the information retained by us?

We only collect information which is necessary for the operation of the web sites and for the provision of the Services. We will not keep your personal information for longer than necessary to provide the Services or as required by law.

## 6\. How is the information used?

We use the personal information which we collect to operate the web sites and to provide the Services and send you details of goods and services, where you have given us your consent to do so.

## 7\. Use of cookies

The use of cookies is common and many web sites use them. A cookie is a small data storage program which is stored by your computer's web browser on your hard drive. Each time your web browser requests a page from our web server the message is sent back to your computer. The message enables the web sites to speed up and simplify the logging on/purchasing process, record your activities and personalise the web site for your use. Any information collected by cookies may be used to personalise the Services available from the web sites to you. We will only use cookies to view information on your computer that was put there by a cookie from our web sites. The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Further information on cookies and the removal of cookies can be found on the [Information Advertising Bureau](http://www.allaboutcookies.com/) website. If you choose to disable cookies your access to the websites may be limited.

## 8\. Accessing and amending your personal information

You may request a copy of all your personal information held by us by contacting the Symbian Data Protection Compliance Officer, Legal Department, Symbian Ltd, 2-6 Boundary Row, Southwark, London SE1 8HP, [privacy@symbian.com](mailto:privacy@symbian.com), tel: +44 (0) 20 7154 1673, fax: +44 (0) 20 7154 1861. Symbian will charge a £10 administration fee for providing the copies.

We will amend any incorrect personal information held by us. We will remove your personal information from our records within 30 days of receiving your notification to do so, subject to any legal requirements to retain such information. Please notify the Symbian Data Protection Compliance Officer, if you believe your personal information held by us is incorrect or you wish to remove your personal information from our records.

## 9\. Disclosure to Third Parties

We will not disclose your personal information to any third parties apart from where you have given us your consent to do so. However, if you register to participate in a Symbian event via the websites your details may be disclosed to other participants in the Symbian event or to members of the public as part of a directory and/or database.

We may ask you to give your consent for us to disclose your personal information to other companies in our group or other selected third parties who may contact you to let you know about goods or services which may be of interest to you.

We may provide sales, traffic and demographic statistics and other related information to third parties but these statistics will not contain any information which could be used to identify any individual customer.

We reserve the right to access and disclose to third parties your personal information to comply with applicable laws and lawful authority requests, to safeguard the proper operation of our systems and to protect ourselves and our customers.

## 10\. Consent/Opt-outs

If you submit personal information through the web sites and do not tick the opt-out boxes set out on the relevant page, then you give consent to the use of the personal information by Symbian and/or other companies selected by us for the purposes described.

## 11\. Transfer of personal information outside the European Economic Area ("EEA")

We will not transfer your personal information outside the EEA with the exception of transfer of information to Symbian offices outside the EEA, and/or (where you have given us your consent to do so) selected third parties, in relation to the provision of the Services.

## 12\. Protection of personal information

We use up to date industry procedures to secure your personal information held by us from unauthorised access, use, disclosure or loss. We may also protect the security of your personal information during transmission using Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL")/encryption software.

## 13\. Children

We do not specifically collect personal information about children and request that children obtain their parents' consent before providing personal information. We recommend that parents actively monitor their children's use of the Internet and the web site.

## 14\. External Web Sites

This privacy policy only applies to the web sites. The web sites may contain links to external web sites. Please note that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of any other web sites you may visit through the web sites.

## 15\. Changes to Privacy Policy

We may amend this privacy policy from time to time. If we make any changes we will post them on the web site, so that you will always be aware of the way we use your personal information.
